

Kleber Lima da Silva

Embedded Systems Engineer | Hardware and Firmware Developer

About Me

Hello! I'm Kleber Lima da Silva. I'm passionate about Electronics and Robotics. I have extensive experience in project development (hardware and firmware) of embedded systems with precision electronics, low consumption, and wireless communication.

Age 33

Email kleber.ufu@gmail.com Phone +55 14 99104-0606

City Marilia, SP, Brazil

Professional Skills

Schematic Design	Bare-Metal and RTOS
PCB Layout	Embedded Linux
Design for Manufacturing	Microcontrollers

Tech Stack



Work Experience

Professional Training Instructor - Electronics at SENAI SP

Feb, 2020 - Oct, 2022

Professional training instructor in electronics (technical design, electricity, building and industrial electrical installations, analog and digital electronic systems, residential and industrial automation, projects).

Hardware and Firmware Engineer at SEYS - Sistemas Inteligentes

Dez, 2017 - June, 2019

Management and development of embedded hardware and firmware projects. Some of the activities: selection of components; PCB schematic and layout development; budgets; DFM (design for manufacturing).

Hardware Engineer at loton Technology

Aug, 2015 - Dez, 2017

Co-founder of the Brazilian startup that created the TON development platform, for learning in robotics, IoT (Internet of Things), automation, etc.

Scientific Research at LASEC - UFU

Feb, 2012 - July, 2015

Project 1: Development of hardware for the autonomous control of a quadcopter. Project 2: Development of a hardware and software prototype for home control by gestures using the Myo armband.

Education

Bachelor of Electronic/Biomedical Engineering from Universidade Federal de Uberlandia

2010 - 2015

Voluntary activities: student tutoring (Biostatistics, Analog Electronics I, Electrical Circuits II and Embedded Systems I); Two scientific initiations PIBIC/CNPq; Member of the Laboratory of Automation, Electronic Systems and Control (LASEC) for 3 years; 2015 Maze Escape Challenge Organizer.

Biomedical Engineering from Polytech Marseille

2013 - 2014

Object Oriented Programming; Labview; Neurophysiology; Automatique; Cardiovascular Biomechanics; Medical Radiophysics; Ultrasound Imaging. MRI-Spectrometry; Tomography; Biomedical Instrumentation II; Matlab; Database; Human Machine Interaction. BRAFITEC / CAPES Program Scholarship.

Electronic Maintenance Technician from SENAI SP

2008 - 2009

1st Place in Electronics - SP Skills 2009; 3rd Place in Industrial Electronics - World Skills Americas 2010.

Contact

City

Marilia, SP, Brazil

Phone

+55 14 99104-0606

Email

kleber.ufu@gmail.com

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/kleberlimadasilva/
- https://www.instagram.com/kleberls6
- https://github.com/krebyy
- http://bit.ly/portfolio-kleber